http://www.sweeteners.org/privacy-policy

About Sweeteners
What are low / no calorie sweeteners ?
About Sweeteners
What are low / no calorie sweeteners ?
About Sweeteners
What are low / no calorie sweeteners ?
About Sweeteners
What are low / no calorie sweeteners ?
Introduction
In this document, “we” and “our” refers to International Sweeteners Association (ISA) of Avenue de Tervueren, 13a, Box 7; 1040 Brussels; Belgium.
The International Sweeteners Association (ISA) is an international non-profit organisation and is registered in Belgium.
This Privacy Policy sets out how we collect, handle, process and store certain information about individuals. These individuals, also knowns as “data subjects” can include ISA members, candidates responding to consultancy offers, business contacts and other people that the association has a relationship with or may need to contact.
ISA is committed to handle personal data in compliance with applicable data protection laws, including EU Regulation 2016/679 on General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). In particular, ISA commits to only collect and process personal data that is: processed fairly, in a transparent way and based on valid legal grounds; obtained for specific lawful purposes; adequate, relevant and not excessive; accurate and kept up to date; not held for longer than necessary; protected in appropriate ways and not transferred outside of the European Economic Area, unless adequate protective measures are in place.
In this privacy policy, we describe what personal data we collect and process, for what purposes, on what legal grounds, who are the recipients, how long such data is retained, whether we transfer it to third parties, and what are your rights as data subjects.
What personal data do we collect?
ISA may collect the following categories of personal data to the extent necessary to achieve the purposes outlined in this policy:
Identification data, such as name, forename, photo, national registration number;
Contact data, such as email address, telephone number, postal address;
Personal information, such as age, date of birth, gender, marital status, citizenship;
Financial data, such as bank account details;
Education and profession and employment data, such as university, specialisation, function, skill sets, past employers.
In most instances, we collect personal data directly from the data subjects, but we may sometimes obtain personal data from third parties (such as the data subject’s employer or from a public authority).
When you supply information to us through our website, you will do so through a secure connection which ensures no one else can view or access your data as you supply it.
Why we process personal data and on what basis?
As part of its general mission, ISA processes personal data for the following purposes:
For general membership administration: ISA has legitimate interests in the processing of personal data of ISA members for the purpose of administering the membership and collecting membership fees. As an AISBL in Belgium (Association internationale sans but lucratif) ISA is also bound by Belgian law with respect to the organisation of general assemblies and board meetings.
For organising events and conferences: ISA processes identification details of individuals who register to participate to events and conferences organised by ISA for the purpose of managing the registration and participation to such events based on the necessity for ISA to meet its obligations as organiser of the events under the general terms and conditions that are expressly accepted by the individuals and/or based on consent for certain personal data.
For website administration purposes: ISA processes identification data from individuals who register themselves on the ISA website and give their express consent to receive newsletters or information from ISA or to connect with the ISA via the ISA’s various digital platforms (Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn etc.).
For contract management purposes: ISA has legitimate interests in the processing of personal data of representatives and contact persons of entities and associations with which ISA contracts (e.g. with respect to services agreements, consultancy agreements and research agreements).
ISA also has a legitimate interest in the processing of personal data to the extent strictly necessary for the purposes of allowing exchanges with individuals who have engaged with ISA by signing up to the ISA newsletter, by taking part in ISA surveys or by contacting the ISA regarding the services delivered by the ISA.
How long do we keep personal data?
ISA will only keep personal data for the time that is strictly necessary to achieve the purpose(s) for which they were collected, e.g. for the duration of a contractual relationship or of a project, and for a period of time thereafter if so required by applicable law or if in the primary interests of the data subjects. ISA does not transfer personal data outside of the EEA.
What are your rights as data subjects and how to exercise them?
As data subject, you have the following rights with respect to personal data we hold about you, subject to applicable legal restrictions:
Right of access to your personal data;
Right to rectification of incorrect or incomplete personal data;
Right to erasure of your personal data;
Right to restriction of processing of your personal data;
Right to data portability, i.e., the right to receive the personal data concerning you in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and to transmit those data to another controller;
Right to object to all or part of the processing, when legally allowed;
Right not to be subject to automated individual decision-making, including profiling within the limits set out by the law;
Right to withdraw consent at any time when we process your personal data based on your consent;
Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in the EU.
If you wish to exercise any of these rights or if you are not satisfied about how we protect your privacy, you should address your request by email together with a copy of your ID (which we will only use to verify your identity), to ISA, as the data controller, at the following address: info@sweeteners.org
ISA will aim to respond to data subject requests within a maximum of 1 month of receipt of the request.
Third party websites
We may from time to time, recommend and link to the websites of partner networks or organisations, to and from the websites of third parties and to and from links to any social media platforms. If you follow a link to any of these websites or social media platforms, please note that these websites and social media platforms should have their own privacy policies, which will govern their use of the information that you provide to them and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. It is your responsibility to check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites or social media platforms.
Cookies
Visits to our website will result in the automatic storage of a small text file (“cookie”) on your computer. The particular behaviour of each user is neither observed nor recorded. The information that we receive and save in the course of a normal visit is used solely within International Sweeteners Association (ISA) for the purpose of optimising this website and its use. It is not used for identification purposes except in the case of attacks that constitute criminal offences or that prevent or influence the functional capacity of our website.
We use cookies to give you the best experience on our site. You can find out more about the cookies we use or disable them in the settings.
Accept
Deny
Close GDPR Cookie Settings
Privacy Overview
Strictly necessary cookies
Third party cookies
Privacy Overview
This website uses cookies so that we can provide you with the best user experience possible. Cookie information is stored in your browser and performs functions such as recognising you when you return to our website and helping our team to understand which sections of the website you find most interesting and useful.
Strictly necessary cookies
This option should be enabled at all times so that we can save your preferences for cookie settings.
If you disable this cookie, we will not be able to save your preferences. This means that each time you visit this site, you will have to enable or disable cookies again.
Enable or Disable Cookies
Third party cookies
This site uses Google Analytics to collect anonymous information such as the number of visitors to the site and the most popular pages.
Keeping this cookie enabled helps us improve our website.
Enable or Disable Cookies
Please enable Strictly Necessary Cookies first so that we can save your preferences!
Enable All
Save Settings
